Finding Aid for Gardner Ackley Papers, 1936-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- US Ambassador to Italy 1968-1969
  - Miscellaneous (Box 36)
- Later career
  The Later career series includes professional correspondence and a variety of subject files. This material came from the Ackley home and was not part of the first two accessions, thus the files of professional correspondence continue the run of files found in the Professional Correspondence series.
  - Professional correspondence
    - 1981 (Box 36)
    - 1982 (Box 36)
    - 1983 (Box 36)
    - 1984 (Box 36)
    - 1985 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous
    - GA bibliography (Box 36)
    - LBJ Presidential Library (Box 36)
    - Meloy, Francis (Box 36)
      (Ambassador to Dominican Republic)
- Personal: Photographs, Scrapbooks, etc.
  The Personal: Photographs, Scrapbooks series consists of photographs, mainly of which were formerly framed. These concern Ackleys career as a member of the Council of Economic Advisers and as Ambassador to Italy. Many of these are official photographs from the White House with Gardner Ackley conversing with (or as part of a group with) President Lyndon Johnson. This series also includes some letters from President Johnson.
  - Letters from President Lyndon B. Johnson 1965, 1968 (Box 37)
  - Diplomas, honorary degree diplomas, award certificates, 1 folders (Box 37)
  - Letters and other materials regarding retirement celebration1983 (Box 37)
  - Scrapbook with clippings and magazine articles relating to GA's appointment to the Council of Economic Advisers 1962-1964 (Box 38)
    (include scattered memorabilia and photograph)
  - Presidential appointments and official greetings of membership in professional organizations (Folder 1)
  - Photographs
    - Album prepared by U.S. Army Southern European Task Force during GA's visit as Ambassador to Italy 1968 (Box 37)
      (album include photos of GA with military personnel)
    - Miscellaneous: photograph and schedule of GA visit to USS Independence October 1968 (Box 37)
    - Portraits; GA speaking (Box 37)
    - With (or of) President John F. Kennedy and President Lyndon B. Johnson (Box 37)
    - With members of the Council of Economic Advisers (Box 37)
    - US Ambassador to Italy period (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous; include University of Michigan Economics Building fire 1981 (Box 37)
  - Photographs, many taken from frames, 50 images approximate
    - With (or of) President Lyndon B. Johnson (Box 38)
    - With (or relating to) Council of Economic Advisers (Box 38)
    - Photographs taken in connection with article in Business Weekly, 1965 (Box 36)
    - Composite photograph portraits of the members of the University of Michigan Dept. of Economics 1981-1982; also photo of earlier faculty (Box 38)